export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A situation where an audience is aware of an action a character is ignorant of is ________",
A: "dramatic irony",
B: "comic relief",
C: "aside",
D: "satire",
answer: "B. didactic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A fictional prose which is neither a novel nor a short story is a/an __________",
A: "allegory",
B: "fable",
C: "novella",
D: "novelette",
answer: "B. anecdote",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Condensed use of language is a dominant feature of  ___________",
A: "comedy",
B: "poetry",
C: "prose",
D: "tragedy",
answer: "B. poetry",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The sudden reversal of a character's fortune in a literary work is _________",
A: "denouement",
B: "hamartia",
C: "hubris",
D: "peripeteia",
answer: "D. peripeteia",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The underlined words illustrate ________",
A: "hyperbole",
B: "irony",
C: "metonymy",
D: "paradox",
answer: "C. metonymy ('words' representing the power to create kingdoms)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. hands and feet in line 4 illustrate _________",
A: "contrast",
B: "litotes",
C: "personification",
D: "synecdoche",
answer: "D. synecdoche (parts representing the whole: hands and feet representing the labor of the people)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. His pen was like the breath of life exemplifies ________",
A: "bathos",
B: "pathos",
C: "satire",
D: "simile",
answer: "D. simile",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Comic relief occurs in ________",
A: "comedies",
B: "pastorals",
C: "romance",
D: "tragedies",
answer: "A. comedies",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Students rarely read Julius Caesar these days illustrates ________",
A: "caesura",
B: "eponym",
C: "oxymoron",
D: "zeugma",
answer: "B. eponym (Julius Caesar's name representing the play)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. In Literature, the term poetic justice applies to __________",
A: "a story that ends well",
B: "characters that are spared death",
C: "the development of a good plot",
D: "the rewarding of good characters and the punishing of bad ones.",
answer: "D. the rewarding of good characters and the punishing of bad ones.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Ascribing human moods to nature, as in a playful-breeze illustrates _________",
A: "humour",
B: "pathetic fallacy",
C: "symbolism",
D: "zeugma",
answer: "B. pathetic fallacy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The end of a performance is followed by ________",
A: "a curtain call",
B: "a curtain raiser",
C: "epilogue",
D: "interlude",
answer: "A. a curtain call",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz (This question seems to be missing)",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Great hearted gentlemen singing this song",
A: "assonance",
B: "consonance",
C: "onomatopoeia",
D: "repetition",
answer: "B. consonance (repetition of consonant sounds)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A short poem with a witty or sarcastic ending is a/an __________",
A: "ballad",
B: "allegory",
C: "epigram",
D: "panegyric",
answer: "C. epigram",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The big boulder blasted the house illustrates _________",
A: "alliteration",
B: "contrast",
C: "irony",
D: "paradox",
answer: "A. alliteration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The dominant literary device used in the lines is ________",
A: "euphemism",
B: "hyperbole",
C: "paradox",
D: "understatement",
answer: "C. paradox",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The feeling of the narrator in the extract is to one of ________",
A: "Confusion",
B: "fatigue",
C: "love",
D: "joy",
answer: "C. Confusion",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following is written by an African playwright?",
A: "She Stoops to Conquer",
B: "A Raisin in the Sun",
C: "Lonely Days",
D: "The Blood of a stranger",
answer: "B. A Raisin in the Sun",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following is written by a Non-African poet?",
A: "Piano and Drums",
B: "The Dining Table",
C: "The Schoolboy",
D: "The Panic of Growing Older",
answer: "C. The Schoolboy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The most suitable title for the passage is ________",
A: "A Savage Struggle at Night",
B: "At Sea on a Stormy Night.",
C: "The Long Heaving Waves",
D: "The Million Voices in the Sea",
answer: "B. At Sea on a Stormy Night.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The predominant use of long vowels in the first sentence heightens the ______ of the waves",
A: "anger",
B: "expanse",
C: "great noise",
D: "endless movement",
answer: "D. endless movement",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The writer's attitude to the scene is one of _________",
A: "anxiety",
B: "awe",
C: "contempt",
D: "indifference",
answer: "B. awe",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The expression million voices is used as _________",
A: "conceit",
B: "euphemism",
C: "hyperbole",
D: "metonymy",
answer: "C. hyperbole",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. A ship in the last line symbolises _________",
A: "despair.",
B: "hope",
C: "pirates",
D: "sailors",
answer: "B. hope",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The theme is about the poet's _________",
A: "broken love affairs.",
B: "fee the stilly night.",
C: "sleepless night.",
D: "yearning for happier times gone",
answer: "D. yearning for happier times gone",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The theme of the poem is presented essentially through ________",
A: "assonance",
B: "contrast.",
C: "paradox",
D: "repetition",
answer: "D. repetition ('Ere slumber's chain has bound me' is repeated)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The two words that give hint of the poet's unhappiness are?",
A: "light and night",
B: "light and shone",
C: "night and dimm'd",
D: "Shone and dimm'd",
answer: "C. night and dimm'd",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The poet refers to memory as being 'fond' and 'sad' because it brings?",
A: "cheers and smiles",
B: "love and joy",
C: "sorrow and pity",
D: "smiles and tears",
answer: "C. sorrow and pity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The meaning of the expression, Ere slumber's chain has bound me is",
A: "after i wake up",
B: "before i sleep",
C: "before i dream",
D: "since i cannot sleep",
answer: "B. before i sleep",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The speaker is _________",
A: "Cassio",
B: "Iago",
C: "Lodovico",
D: "Roderigo",
answer: "A. Duke",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The listener's initial reaction to the speech is one of _________",
A: "anger",
B: "defiance",
C: "disbelief",
D: "regret",
answer: "C. Brabantio",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The underlined expression implies an attitude of __________",
A: "callousness",
B: "hypocrisy",
C: "racism",
D: "tribalism",
answer: "C. Othello's elopement with Desdemona",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. ... y' are robbed! refers to",
A: "Brabantio's r-ejection of Othello",
B: "Desdemona's stout defense of Othello",
C: "Iago's stealing of Rodrigo's purse",
D: "Othello's elopement with Desdemona",
answer: "B. console the addressee",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The speaker is ________",
A: "at the citadel of Cyprus",
B: "In front of Brabantio's house",
C: "In the council chamber",
D: "outside the sagittary",
answer: "C. it is useful not to bemoan one's loss",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The speaker is",
A: "cassio",
B: "Iago",
C: "Duke",
D: "Roderigo",
answer: "C. lago and Roderigo",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The speaker is addressing",
A: "Cassio",
B: "Iago",
C: "Othelo",
D: "Roderigo",
answer: "A. hatred for Othello",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The mood is that of",
A: "deceit",
B: "envy",
C: "hatred",
D: "regret",
answer: "B. enriching lago",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. .... so good a commander refers to",
A: "Brabantio",
B: "Duke",
C: "Othelo",
D: "Roderigo",
answer: "D. you will have succeeded in seducing her",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The underlined expression exemplifies __________",
A: "antithesis",
B: "apostrophe",
C: "chiasmus",
D: "euphemism",
answer: "C. friendliness (though insincere)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. .. he ..., referred to by Speaker X, is __________",
A: "Brabantio",
B: "Gratiano",
C: "Montano",
D: "Lodovico",
answer: "A. Othello",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. ..do a desperate turn means _______",
A: "commit suicide",
B: "confront Duke",
C: "disown Desdemona",
D: "kill Othello",
answer: "C. the citadel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Speaker Y's speech shows that _________",
A: "Cassio is to blame",
B: "Emilia is to blame",
C: "he is unrepentant",
D: "she is regretful",
answer: "D. Lodovico and others",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Speaker Y has just ______",
A: "discovered lago's plan",
B: "killed, Desdemona",
C: "ordered the arrest of lago",
D: "promoted Cassio",
answer: "C. express the speaker's acceptance of guilt",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Just after this dialogue __________",
A: "Cassia is killed",
B: "Emilia realises her culpability",
C: "lago gloats over his success",
D: "Roderigo fights Cassio",
answer: "A. he killing of Desdemona",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The speaker is _________",
A: "Bianca",
B: "Cassio",
C: "Desdemona",
D: "Emilia",
answer: "B. Othello",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The speaker has just been threatened by ________",
A: "Cassio",
B: "lago",
C: "Lodovico",
D: "Othello",
answer: "B. Othello's departure for Cyprus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. What has just happened is that _______",
A: "Emilia has confirmed her mistress's guilt",
B: "lago has openly confessed his crime",
C: "Othello has murdered his wife",
D: "Roderigo has realised lago is a fraud",
answer: "C. sailing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Soon after this, the Speaker ________",
A: "attempts to run away",
B: "is arrested by Lodovico",
C: "is killed by lago",
D: "shows remorse",
answer: "D. fulfilment as a warrior",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. This stage of the play is known as the _________",
A: "climax",
B: "conflict",
C: "dennouement",
D: "expos",
answer: "C. hyperbolical",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]